Contact

khaledzaheerbaber@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/khalid-z-baber-17451918b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Web Services
Dotnet core
ASP.NET MVC

Certifications

Exam 487: Developing Microsoft Azure and Web Services

Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3

MCSD: App Builder — Certified 2020

Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA)

MCSD: App Builder — Certified 2020

Khalid Z. baber

Senior Software Engineer

Pakistan

Summary

More than 8+ years of digital transformation experience in HR, Payroll, Employee Appraisal, Document Management, Task Management, Online Bookings industries with some of the best companies and ministry in the world like APCOA Parking Sverige AB Sweden, Ministry of Awqaf Kuwait, Burgan National Information Systems Company Kuwait, Alalamiah Technology Group (ATG) as Dot Net developer, Sr. Dot Net developer, Sr. Software Engineer.

Professional Achievements are Microsoft Certified Developer (MCSD), Microsoft Certified Solution Associate (MCSA), Certificate of Appreciation from Ministry of Awqaf Kuwait.

Hands on Experience with

Framework: .NET, .NET Core

Design patterns: MVC, MVVM, Repository, Unit of Work, Singleton,

Factory, Dependency Injection

Architecture: monolith, N-Layer, microservice, clean architecture,

CQCRS

Entity Framework, ADO .NET

Write effective Rest APIs, WCF Services

Programming Languages: C#

Database: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, NoSQL (Elastic Search) Reporting: PowerBI, SSRS, Crystal Report, ETL, Data warehouse

Front End: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Angular 2, Knockout Js,

JavaScript

CI/CD: TFS/GIT hub, Docker, Kubernetes, Bamboo, Octopus Cloud: Azure Function, Azure Queues, Azure BLOB Storages,

RABBIT MQ

Methodology: SDLC, Agile, Scrum.

Gathered user requirements, designed the framework using UML that included identifying the use cases and its surroundings, drawing use case diagrams, identifying classes, drawing class diagrams and sequence diagrams.

Exceptional knowledge on SOLID Principles, Object Oriented Programming (OOPS) concepts.

Proficient in writing Unit Test, Integration test using NUnit Testing Framework.

Proven ability to analyze problems, root causes, and develop innovative solutions to business challenges and streamlining operations.

Always has the passion to learn new technologies.

Experience

Norandum AB Sr. Software Engineer July 2019 - Present (2 years 9 months) Pakistan

As Appointed Resource to APCOA Parking AG which is the Europe's largest parking management company. It manages over 1.4m parking spaces across 13 countries, and employs approximately 4,500 people

I Work together with the Project Management and Product Owner to plan and execute projects, ensure that we have appropriate product and technical specifications, direction, and resources to deliver products effectively by establishing realistic estimates for timelines while ensuring that projects remain on target to meet deadlines

Evolve the existing software system applications and architecture in various areas as needed

Develop shared libraries and components to use across the teams to be consumed at server side.

Participate in daily scrum meetings and coordinate for release and sprint planning

perform code reviews to maintain secure and healthy code repository.

Maintain and troubleshoot CI/CD pipeline for automated delivery of our web services.

Burgan National Information Systems Company Sr. Software Engineer August 2017 - March 2019 (1 year 8 months) Kuwait

Work with development teams and product managers to ideate software solutions

Design client-side and server-side architecture

Build the front-end of applications through appealing visual design

Develop and manage well-functioning databases and applications

Write effective APIs

Test software to ensure responsiveness and efficiency
Troubleshoot, debug and upgrade software
Create security and data protection settings
Build features and applications with a mobile responsive design
Write technical documentation

Alalamiah Technology Group (ATG)
Dotnet Developer
June 2014 - February 2017 (2 years 9 months)
Kuwait

As Appointed Resource to Ministry of Awqaf Kuwait I worked as developer and Involved in Analysis, Detail Design, Coding, Unit Testing and support Integration & Performance Testing of ministry of awaqaf solutions that include but not limited to following major systems:

- Task and Complaint Management System.
- Employee Performance and appraisal system.
- Document Management System

And achieve the performance appreciation award from ministry of awqaf Kuwait

Urvision Web Developer March 2010 - April 2014 (4 years 2 months) Kuwait Islam Presentation Committee Kuwait Software Developer October 2004 - January 2010 (5 years 4 months) Kuwait

Mansha Brothers Developer October 2003 - July 2004 (10 months) Pakistan

Education

Iqra University (Official)

Master of Computer Applications - MCA, Computer Software

Engineering · (2000 - 2002)

University of the Punjab BSC, Double Math And Physics · (1998 - 2000)